Hi. I've got an appointment with Mr. Ullman.
你好  我和乌尔曼先生有预约
My name is Jack Torrance.
我叫杰克·托伦斯
His office is the first door on the left.
他的办公室是左手边第一间
Thank you.
谢谢
- Mr. Ullman? - Yes.
-乌尔曼先生  -正是
- I'm Jack Torrance. - Oh, come on in, Jack.
-我是杰克·托伦斯  -快请进  杰克
Very nice to meet you.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you too, Mr. Ullman.
我也很高兴认识你  乌尔曼先生
- This is my secretary, Susie. - Hello.
-这是我的秘书  苏希  -你好
- Susie, how do you do? - Any trouble finding us?
-苏希  你好  -我们这里难找吗
No problem at all. I made the trip in 3 and a half hours.
一点不难找  我三个半小时就到了
That's very good time.
那真是算很快了
Sit down a minute, Jack.
快请坐吧  杰克
Just make yourself at home.
在这千万别拘束
Would you like some coffee?
要来杯咖啡吗
If you're having some, I wouldn't mind. Thanks.
如果有的话  就来点吧  谢谢
- Susie. - Sure.
-苏希  -好
And would you ask Bill Watson to join us.
去叫比尔·沃森来跟我们一起
Yes, I will.
好的  我这就去
Mom?
妈妈
Yeah?
怎么了
Do you really want to go and live in that hotel for the winter?
你真的想去住在那个酒店里过冬天吗
Sure I do.
当然了
It'll be lots of fun.
肯定很好玩
Yeah. I guess so.
好吧  应该是吧
Anyway, there's hardly anybody to play with around here.
反正  这里也没什么人一起玩
I know. It always takes a little time to make new friends.
我知道  结交新朋友总是需要花些时间的
Yeah, I guess so.
是啊  或许是吧
What about Tony?
托尼呢
He's looking forward to the hotel, I bet.
我猜他肯定很期待去酒店
No, I ain't, Mrs. Torrance.
不  我才不呢  托伦斯夫人
Now, come on, Tony. Don't be silly.
拜托  托尼  别犯傻了
I don't want to go there, Mrs. Torrance.
我不想去那里  托伦斯夫人
How come you don't want to go?
你为什么不想去呢
I just don't.
我就是不想去
Let's just wait and see.
那我们就走着瞧吧
We're all going to have a real good time.
我们都会玩得很开心的
Bill, I'd like you to meet Jack Torrance.
比尔  我想介绍你认识一下杰克·托伦斯
- How do you do, Bill? - How do you do.
-你好  比尔  -你好
- Nice to meet you. - Pleasure to meet you.
-很高兴认识你  -很高兴认识你
Grab a chair, Bill. Join in.
坐吧  比尔  一起聊聊
Jack is going to take care of the Overlook for us this winter.
杰克今年冬天会帮我们照看眺望酒店
I'd like you to take him around place soon as we're through.
等我们谈完  希望你带他四处转转
Fine.
好的
Jack is a schoolteacher.
杰克是学校里的老师
Uh, formerly a schoolteacher.
以前是老师
What line of work are you in now?
你现在做什么工作
I'm a writer.
我是个作家
Teaching's been more or less a way of making ends meet.
教书差不多就是为了糊口而已
This ought to be quite a change for you.
如今这样对你来说应该是个很大的变化
Well, I'm looking for a change.
我很期待有变化
Our people in Denver recommended Jack very highly,
我们在丹佛的人强烈推荐杰克
and for once...
这一次
I agree with them.
我同意他们说的
Let's see, where were we?
刚刚说到哪了
I was ,yeah, about to explain...
我刚刚  准备给你解释
that our season here runs from may 15th to October 30th.
我们的营业季是从5月15号到10月30号
Then we close down completely until the following May.
然后彻底停业  到第二年的5月再开业
Do you mind if I ask why you do that?
我能问问为什么吗
It seems to me that the skiing up here would be fantastic.
在我看来在这里滑雪应该会很棒
It would be. The problem is the enormous cost...
的确是的  问题在于要花费巨大的成本
it would be to keep the road to Sidewinder open.
维持到萨德温德镇的路面能够通行
It's a 25-mile stretch of road.
那是段25英里的路
It gets 20 feet of snow during the winter.
冬天的降雪厚度能有20英尺
There's just no way to make it economically feasible to keep it clear.
要保持路面畅通  从经济上来看是完全不划算的
When the place was built in 1907...
1907年建这个地方的时候
there was very little interest in winter sports.
人们对冬季运动尚不感兴趣
This site was chosen for its seclusion and scenic beauty.
选择这里完全是看中其幽静的环境和美丽的风景
It's certainly got plenty of that.
这里的确够幽静和美丽的
That's right.
没错
Did they give you any idea in Denver...
在丹佛时  他们有没有告诉你
about what the job entails?
这份工作具体是做什么的
Only in a very general way.
就大致说了一下
The winters can be fantastically cruel.
冬季真的会无比残酷
The basic idea is to cope with the very costly damage...
基本就是要应对高额的损坏
and depreciation which can occur.
以及可能出现的折旧
This consists mainly of running the boiler...
这主要包括烧锅炉
heating different parts of the hotel on a daily rotating basis...
每天例行给酒店的不同区域供暖
repairing damage as it occurs...
出现损坏及时修理
and doing repairs so the elements can't get a foothold.
及时修理小毛病就不会变成大问题
That sounds fine to me.
我觉得没有问题
Physically, it's not a very demanding job.
从体力上说  这份工作要求不高
The only thing that can
在冬天  唯一一件
get a bit trying here during the winter...
可能会有点难熬的事情
is a tremendous sense of isolation.
就是会有强烈的孤独感
Well, that just happens to be exactly what I'm looking for.
那恰恰就是我想寻求的
I'm outlining a new writing project.
我正在写新作品的大纲
And, five months of peace is just what I want.
五个月宁静的时光正是我想要的
That's very good, Jack.
那很好  杰克
Because, for some people...
因为  对有的人来说
solitude ...and isolation...
孤独  与世隔绝
can, of itself, become a problem.
本身  就会成为问题
Not for me.
我不会
How about your wife and son?
你夫人和儿子呢
Do you think they'll take to it?
你觉得他们能接受吗
They'll love it.
他们会很喜欢的
Great.
好极了
Well, before I turn you over to Bill,
在我把你交接给比尔之前
there's one other thing I think we should talk about.
我觉得还有一件事我们需要聊聊
I don't want to sound melodramatic,
我也不想耸人听闻
but it's something been known to give a few people
但是这件事的确会让有些人
second thoughts about the job.
犹豫到底要不要接受这份工作
I'm intrigued.
我很有兴趣知道
I don't suppose they tell you anything in Denver
我觉得在丹佛时他们应该没告诉你
about the tragedy we had up here during the winter of 1970.
1970年冬天发生在这里的一起悲剧事件
I don't believe they did.
他们似乎的确没说
My predecessor in this job
我这个职位的前任负责人
hired a man named Charles Grady as the winter caretaker.
雇了一个叫查尔斯·格拉迪的人当冬季管理员
He came up with his wife and two little girls
他是带着夫人和两个女儿一起来的
of about 8 and 10.
一个8岁  一个10岁
He had a good employment record,
他过去的工作记录很好
good references.
推荐信都对他赞不绝口
And from what I've been told,
据我所知道的信息
he seemed like a completely normal individual.
他似乎是一个非常正常的人
But at some point during the winter
但是在冬天的某个时候
he must have suffered
他一定是经受了
some kind of a complete mental breakdown.
某种程度上的精神崩溃
He ran amuck and...
他发狂了  然后...
killed his family with an ax.
用一把斧子杀了全家人
Stacked them neatly in a room in the west wing, and then he...
把他们整齐地码在西翼的一个房间里  然后他...
he put both barrels of his shotgun in his mouth.
他把双管猎枪对准了嘴里  举枪自尽了
The police...
警方...
they thought that it was what the old-timers used to call cabin fever.
警方认为这就是人们以前常说的幽闭症
A kind of claustrophobic reaction which can occur
这种幽闭恐惧反应可能会出现在
when people are shut in together over long periods of time.
一群人被困在一起很长时间之后
That is...
那还真是...
quite a story.
相当离奇的故事
Yeah, it is.
是啊  的确
It's still hard for me to believe it actually happened here.
我还是很难相信这事真的是在这里发生的
But it did.
但事实如此
And, uh
然后
I think you can appreciate why I wanted to tell you about it.
我觉得你应该能理解我为什么要告诉你
I certainly can.
我当然理解
I also understand why your people in Denver
我也理解为什么你在丹佛的那些手下
left it for you to tell me.
把这事留给你来亲自告诉我
Obviously, some people can be put off
显然  有些人一想到
by the idea of staying alone in a place
要在发生过这种事的地方
where something like that actually happened.
单独待这么久的时间  的确会打退堂鼓
Well, you can rest assured Mr. Ullman,
你大可安心  乌尔曼先生
that's not going to happen with me.
我不会打退堂鼓的
And as far as my wife is concerned
至于我夫人那边
I'm sure she'll be absolutely fascinated when I tell her.
我相信等我告诉她  她会被深深地吸引住
She's a confirmed ghost story and horror film addict.
她是个忠实的鬼故事  恐怖电影爱好者
Tony, do you think dad'll get the job?
托尼  你觉得爸爸能拿到这份工作吗
He already did.
他已经拿到了
He's going to phone Wendy up in a few minutes to tell her.
几分钟后他就要打给温蒂告诉她了
Hello.
喂
- Hi, babe. - Hi, hon. How's it going?
-嗨  宝贝  -嗨  亲爱的  还顺利吗
Great. Look, I'm at the hotel
好极了  我还在酒店里
and I still have a awful lot to go through.
接下来有一堆事情要去做
I don't think I can get home before 9:00 or 10:00.
我觉得我9点甚至10点前是到不了家了
Sounds like you got the job.
听起来你已经得到这份工作了
Right. It's a beautiful place.
没错  这地方很美
You and Danny are going to love it.
你和丹尼肯定会喜欢的
Tony, why don't you want to go to the hotel?
托尼  你为什么不想去那家酒店
I don't know.
我不知道
You do too know. Now come on, tell me.
你肯定知道  快点告诉我
I don't want to.
我不想说
Please.
拜托啦
No.
不
Now, Tony, tell me.
托尼  告诉我
Now, hold your eyes still so I can see.
现在把眼睛睁开让我看看
That's good. Now the other one.
很好  另一只
Good boy.
好孩子
Now, Danny
丹尼
when you were brushing your teeth
你记不记得在刷牙的时候
do you remember if you smelled anything funny
闻到什么奇怪的气味
or saw any bright, flashing lights
或者看到什么强烈的闪光
or anything at all strange?
或是任何奇怪的东西
No.
没有
Do you remember when you were brushing your teeth?
你还记得你之前在刷牙吗
Yes.
记得
What's the next thing you remember after you were brushing your teeth?
刷牙之后紧接着发生的事  你还记得什么
My mom was saying, "Wake up. Wake up, Danny, wake up. "
我妈妈在说  "醒醒  醒醒  丹尼  醒醒"
Now, Danny, can you remember what you were doing
丹尼  你还记不记得
just before you started brushing your teeth?
在开始刷牙之前你在做什么
Talking to Tony.
和托尼说话
Is Tony one of your animals?
托尼是你的宠物吗
No. He's a little boy that lives in my mouth.
不  他是住在我嘴里的小男孩
Tony's his imaginary friend.
托尼是他的幻想好友
If you were to open your mouth now, could I see Tony?
你现在能不能张开嘴  让我见见托尼
No.
不行
Why not?
为什么
Because he hides.
因为他藏起来了
Where does he go?
他去哪了
To my stomach.
进我肚子里了
Does Tony ever tell you to do things?
托尼让你做过什么事吗
I don't want to talk about Tony anymore.
我不想再聊托尼了
Okay.
好吧
That's fine.
没关系
All right, Danny.
好了  丹尼
I'm going to ask you to do me a favor
我想请你帮我个忙
and stay quietly in bed for the rest of the day. Okay?
今天都乖乖地躺在床上  好吗
Do I have to?
一定要这样吗
Yes. I'd like you to.
是的  我希望你听话
We're going in the other room for a few minutes and talk.
我们去另一个房间聊一会儿
I'll come back and check on you.
我会回来看你的
-Okay?  - Okay.
-好吗  -好的
Bye.
再见
- Shall we go into the living room? - Yes.
-我们到客厅去吧  -好的
- Please. - Thank you.
-请坐  -谢谢
Mrs. Torrance, I don't think you have anything to worry about.
托伦斯夫人  我觉得你无需担心
I'm quite sure there's nothing physically wrong with Danny.
我非常肯定丹尼的身体没有任何问题
Yeah?
是吗
He seems absolutely fine now.
他现在看上去没有任何问题
But you should've seen him.
但你真该看看他之前的样子
I know.
我懂的
Kids can scare you to death.
小孩出点事能把做父母的吓死
But believe me, these episodes are not at all uncommon.
但相信我  这种突然的发作一点也不罕见
And they look much worse than they are.
虽然看起来很糟  但实际情况并非如此
But what was the matter with him?
不过他到底是怎么回事
Mrs. Torrance, Most of the time,
托伦斯夫人  很多时候
these episodes with kids are never explained.
孩子的这种突然发作都无法解释
They're brought on by emotional factors and rarely occur again.
通常是由情感因素引起的  很少会再次出现
They're more akin to autohypnosis
那更像是自我催眠
A kind of self-induced trance.
一种自发式的催眠行为
If it reoccurs, which I doubt
如果再发生  尽管我觉得不大可能
we can always think about having some tests done.
可以考虑做一些检查
No, thank you.
不了  谢谢你
I'm sure you're right.
我相信你说得对
Have you been in Boulder long, Mrs. Torrance?
你在博尔德待了很久吗  托伦斯夫人
Only about three months.
刚来大约三个月
We're from Vermont. My husband was teaching school there.
我们是从佛蒙特州来的  我丈夫以前在那教书
Did the appearance of Danny's imaginary friend...
丹尼那位幻想好友的出现...
Tony.
托尼
Did Tony's first appearance
托尼的初次出现
happen to coincide with your arrival here?
是否恰好是你们搬来这里的时候
No.
不是
Let's see...
我想想...
I guess Danny started talking to Tony
我想丹尼开始跟托尼说话
about the time we put him in nursery school.
大约是在我们送他进幼儿园的时候
Did he adjust well to school?
他对于学校生活适应得好吗
No.
不好
He didn't like it too much at first.
起先他不太喜欢上学
Then he had an injury, so we kept him out for a while and
然后他受了伤  所以我们有阵子没让他去上学
Yeah, I guess that's about
没错  差不多就是那时候
when I first noticed he was talking to Tony.
我发现他在跟托尼说话的
What sort of injury did he have?
他受了什么伤
He dislocated his shoulder.
他的肩膀脱臼了
How did he manage to do that?
怎么弄的
It was just one of those things, you know.
就是小孩子常见的那种情况  你懂的
Purely an accident.
纯粹是意外
My husband had been drinking and
我丈夫一直在酗酒
he came home about three hours late.
他那天晚回来三个多小时
So he wasn't exactly in the greatest mood that night.
那晚他心情不太好
And Danny had scattered some of his school papers all over the room
丹尼把书本和作业纸弄得满屋子都是
and my husband grabbed his arm to pull him away from them.
我丈夫抓住他的胳膊  把他拉开
It's just the sort of thing you do 100 times with a child
就是父母常会对小孩做的那种事
you know, in a park or in the street.
在公园里  或街上  都很常见
But on this particular occasion
但那一次
my husband just used too much strength
我丈夫用力过猛
and he injured Danny's arm.
伤到了丹尼的胳膊
Anyway, something good did come out of it all
不过  这事还是有些好处的
because he said:
因为他说
"Wendy, I'm never going to touch another drop.
"温蒂  我再也不会喝一滴酒了
And if I do, you can leave me. "
如果我再喝  你就离开我"
And he didn't.
然后他就再没喝过酒了
He hasn't had any alcohol in 5 months.
他五个月没有沾酒了
Boy.
天呐
We must really be high up. The air feels so different.
我们一定在很高的地方  空气都感觉很不同
Dad?
爸爸
Yes?
什么事
I'm hungry.
我饿了
You should've eaten your breakfast.
你应该吃早餐的
We'll get you something as soon as we get to the hotel. Okay?
等到了酒店我就给你弄东西吃  好吗
Okay, Mom.
好吧  妈妈
Wasn't it around here that the Donner party got snowbound?
唐纳大队不就是在这里被雪困住的吗
I think that was farther west, in the Sierras.
我觉得应该是更靠西的地方  在内华达山脉
What was the Donner party?
什么是唐纳大队
They were a party of settlers in covered wagon times.
是西部大开发时期的一群移民
They got snowbound one winter in the mountains.
有年冬天  他们被大雪困在了大山里
They had to resort to cannibalism in order to stay alive.
为了活命  他们不得不靠吃人肉为生
You mean they ate each other up?
你是说他们把自己人给吃了
They had to in order to survive.
只有这样才能生存下来
Jack.
杰克
Don't worry, Mom.
别担心  妈妈
I know all about cannibalism. I saw it on TV.
我知道关于食人的事  我在电视上看过
See, it's okay.
瞧吧  没事的
He saw it on the television.
他在电视上看过
- What time does the plane leave? - 8:30.
-飞机什么时候起飞  -8点半
That gives us plenty of time to go over everything first.
那我们还有足够的时间把各项事宜再过一遍
- Goodbye, Mr. Ullman. - Bye.
-再见  乌尔曼先生  -再见
Good morning, Jack. I hope you haven't been waiting too long.
早上好  杰克  希望没让你等太久
No problem. In fact we had time to grab a bite to eat.
没关系  刚好让我们有时间吃点东西
Good. Glad you made it before they shut down the kitchen.
那就好  很高兴你们在厨房关停前赶到了
- Hi. - Is your family having a look around?
-你好  -你的家人到处看过了吗
No, my son's discovered the games room.
没有  我儿子发现了游戏室
- Has your luggage been brought in? - Right there.
-行李都拿进来了吧  -就在那边
Oh, fine.
好的
In view of all the ground we have to cover today
鉴于我们今天要带你了解不少地方
I suggest we have a quick look at your apartment
我建议我们先快速看一下你们的公寓
and get started straight away.
然后立刻开始
Bill, would you have the Torrances' things
比尔  你能安排先把托伦斯一家的东西
brought to their apartment.
送到他们的公寓去吗
- Fine. - I'd better collect my family first.
-好的  -我最好先叫一下我的家人
Oh, yes.
好的
This is our Colorado Lounge.
这里是我们的科罗拉多休闲室
It's beautiful.
真漂亮
My God!
我的天啊
This place is fantastic, isn't it, hon?
这里真是美极了  不是吗  亲爱的
It sure is.
当然
I've never seen anything like this before.
我从没见过这样的东西
Are all these Indian designs authentic?
这些印第安风格的设计都是真品吗
I believe they're based mainly on Navajo and Apache motifs.
好像主要是根据纳瓦霍族和阿帕切族的图案设计的
They're really gorgeous.
真的太美了
As a matter of fact
实际上
this is probably the most gorgeous hotel I've ever seen.
这可能是我见过的最美的酒店了
This old place has had an illustrious past.
这家老酒店有着辉煌的历史
In its heyday, it was one of the stopping place for the jet setters
在其全盛时期  曾住满了社会名流
even before anybody knew what a jet set was.
即便那时大家都还不知道社会名流是什么意思
We had four presidents who stayed here.
有四位总统曾在此住过
Lots of movie stars.
很多电影明星
Royalty?
有皇室的人吗
All the best people.
都是最上层的人物
This is the staff wing of the hotel.
这里是酒店的员工宿舍侧楼
None of the other bedrooms are heated during the winter.
其它卧室冬天都不供暖
- Goodbye, Mr. Ullman. - Goodbye, girls.
-再见  乌尔曼先生  -再见  姑娘们
And here are your quarters.
这就是你们的住处
Living room, bedroom, bathroom.
起居室  卧室  洗手间
And a small bedroom for your son.
还有给你们的儿子住的小房间
Perfect for a child.
非常适合小孩子
- Yeah. - Yes.
-是啊  -是的
Well, then. Place is very nicely self-contained.
好了  这房子独门独户  不用跟别人共用设施
Easy to keep.
也好打理
Cozy.
舒适
Yes, very cozy for a family.
是的  非常适合一家人居住
If you feel like spreading out
如果你们想换个环境
you have the rest of the hotel to move around in.
酒店的其他地方也随便你们住
Well, it's very...
这里真是...
homey.
太有家的感觉了
Yeah.
是啊
This is our famous hedge maze.
这里是我们著名的树篱迷宫
It's quite an attraction here. The walls are 13 feet high
算是这里的一处独特景点吧  墙有13英尺高
and the hedge is as old as the hotel itself.
树篱和酒店一样历史悠久
A lot of fun,
很好玩
but I wouldn't want to go in there
但我一般是不会进去的
unless I had an hour to spare to find my way out.
除非我有一小时的空闲时间用来找出路
When was the Overlook built?
眺望酒店是什么时候建成的
Construction started in 1907.
1907年开始建造
It was finished in 1909.
1909年完工
The site's supposed to be on an Indian burial ground.
这里曾经是一座印第安坟场
And I believe they actually had to repel
据我所知  他们在施工时
a few Indian attacks as they were building it.
不得不打退几次印第安人的袭击
That's our Snowcat.
那是我们的雪地车
Can you both drive a car?
你们都会开车吗
Yes.
会
That's fine.
那就好
Because basically the Snowcat operates very much like a car.
因为驾驶雪地车基本和开车一样
It won't take you long to get the hang of it.
很快就能掌握诀窍了
As a matter of fact,
事实上
we brought a decorator in from Chicago just last year
我们去年从芝加哥请了一位设计师
to refurbish this part of the hotel.
给酒店的这一部分进行重新装修
He sure did a beautiful job.
他确实装修得很不错
Pink and gold are my favorite colors.
粉色和金色是我最喜欢的颜色
Well, this is our Gold Ballroom.
这里是我们的金色舞厅
I'll say!
我就说嘛
We can accommodate up to 300 people here very comfortably.
这里可以轻松容纳三百人
Boy, I bet you we could really have a good party in this room.
天呐  我们可以在这里办一场盛大的派对
I'm afraid you won't do too well here
恐怕你们办不起来多么盛大的派对
unless you brought supplies.
除非你们能自带物资
We always remove the booze from the premises when we shut down.
我们停业时  会将酒全部撤走
That reduces the insurance we normally have to carry.
那可以减少我们通常得承担的保险费用
We don't drink.
我们不喝酒
Then you're in luck.
那你们走运了
Dick, come on over and say hello to Mr. and Mrs. Torrance.
迪克  快过来跟托伦斯夫妇打个招呼
This is Dick Hallorann, our head chef.
这位是迪克·哈洛兰  我们的主厨
- Mr. Hallorann, I'm Jack. - Glad to meet you, Jack.
-哈洛兰先生  我是杰克  -很高兴认识你  杰克
This is my wife, Winifred.
这位是我妻子  温妮芙德
- Glad to meet you, Winifred. - Nice to meet you.
-很高兴认识你  温妮芙德  -很高兴认识你
The Torrances are gonna take care of the Overlook for us this winter.
托伦斯夫妇今年冬天会替我们照料眺望酒店
That's just great. How do you folks like our hotel so far?
太好了  你们目前觉得这个酒店怎么样
It's just wonderful.
简直棒极了
Hi, Danny!
嗨  丹尼
I found him outside looking for you.
我发现他在外面找你们
Dan, did you get tired of bombing the universe?
丹  你厌倦轰炸宇宙了吗
Yeah.
是的
Come on over here.
过来
- Thanks. - Thank you, Susie.
-谢谢  -谢谢你  苏希
Dick, if you're ready to do it now,
迪克  如果你准备好了
I think it'd be a good idea if you could show Mrs. Torrance the kitchen
我觉得你可以带托伦斯夫人去看看厨房
while I continue on with Jack.
我再继续跟杰克交代交代
It would be a pleasure. Right this way, Mrs. Torrance.
非常乐意  这边请  托伦斯夫人
Great. See you later, hon.
太棒了  待会儿见  亲爱的
Bye, darling.
回见  亲爱的
Mrs. Torrance, your husband introduced you as Winifred.
托伦斯夫人  你丈夫介绍你时  叫你温妮芙德
Now, are you a "Winnie," or a "Freddie"?
那我应该叫你温妮还是芙莱蒂
I'm a Wendy.
叫我温蒂就行
Oh, Wendy. That's nice. That's the prettiest.
温蒂啊  真好听  再好听不过了
God, this is the kitchen, huh?
天啊  这厨房太气派了
Yeah, this is it.
没错  正是
How do you like it, Danny? Is it big enough for you?
你觉得怎么样  丹尼  够大吗
Yeah. It's the biggest place I ever seen.
是的  这是我见过的最大的地方
Yeah, this whole place is such an enormous maze.
是啊  这里简直就是一个巨大的迷宫
I feel like I'll have to
我觉得每次进来这儿
leave a trail of breadcrumbs every time I come in.
都得撒面包屑  标记返回的路
Don't let it get you down, Mrs. Torrance.
别灰心  托伦斯夫人
It's big, but it still ain't nothing but a kitchen.
这里是很大  但也不过是个厨房而已
And a lot of this stuff you'll never have to touch.
而且这里的很多东西你连碰都不用碰
I wouldn't know what to do with it if I did.
就算真让我碰  我也不知道怎么用
Well, one thing for sure, you don't have to worry about food.
至少你们丝毫不用担心食物的问题
because ou folks could eat up here a whole year
因为你们一家可以在这里吃上一整年
and never have the same menu twice.
菜单都不带重样的
Now, right here is our walk-in freezer.
这里是我们的步入式冷冻室
Now, this is where we keep all of our meat.
我们将所有肉类都储存在这里
You got 15 rib roasts...
15扇肋排
30 ten-pound bags of hamburger.
30袋汉堡肉  每袋重10磅
We got 12 turkeys, about 40 chickens...
12只火鸡  大概40只鸡
50 sirloin steaks, two dozen of pork roast...
50块西冷牛排  24卷猪排
and 20 legs of lamb. Do you like lamb, Doc?
还有20只羊腿  你喜欢羊肉吗  博士
- No. - You don't?
-不喜欢  -不喜欢吗
Well, what's your favorite food, then?
那你最喜欢吃什么
French fries and ketchup.
炸薯条配番茄酱
Well, I think we can manage that too, Doc.
那也没问题  博士
Come along, now. Watch your step.
跟我来  小心脚下
Mr. Hallorann...
哈洛兰先生
how'd you know we call him Doc?
你怎么知道我们叫他博士
Beg your pardon?
你说什么
Doc. You called Danny "Doc" twice just now.
「博士」  你刚才两次那样叫丹尼
- I did? - Yeah.
-是吗  -是啊
We call him Doc sometimes,
我们有时候叫他博士
like in the Bugs Bunny cartoons.
就像兔八哥卡通片里的博士
But how did you know that?
但你是怎么知道的
Well, I guess I probably heard you call him that.
我想可能是因为我听见你那样叫过他吧
Well, it's possible. But I honestly don't remember
有可能  但我真不记得
calling him that since we've been with you.
我们见面之后  我那样叫过他
Well, anyway, he looks like a Doc, doesn't he?
他看起来就像个博士  对不对
What's up, Doc?
「还好吗  博士」
Now, this is the storeroom.
好了  这里是储藏室
In here, Mrs. Torrance,
托伦斯夫人  在这里面
is where we keep all the dried goods and the canned goods.
存放着我们所有的干货和罐头
We got canned fruits and vegetables...
有水果罐头  蔬菜罐头
canned fish and meats, hot and cold cereals.
鱼罐头  肉罐头  各种冷吃热吃麦片
Post Toasties, Corn Flakes, Sugar Puffs...
博斯特麦片  玉米片  膨化甜麦片
Rice Krispies, oatmeal, Wheatena and Cream of Wheat.
脆米麦片  燕麦片  脆小麦麦片  还有麦乳
You got a dozen jugs of black molasses.
几十罐黑糖蜜
We got 60 boxes of dried milk...
60盒奶粉
How'd you like some ice cream, Doc?
你想吃冰激凌吗  博士
Sociables, finger rolls...
饼干  手指卷面包
and 7 kinds of what have you.
还有七种其他的
Now, we've got dried peaches, dried apricots...
有桃干  杏干
dried raisins and dried prunes.
葡萄干还有西梅干
You know, Mrs. Torrance,
托伦斯夫人
you got to keep regular if you want to be happy.
想过得快乐  就得保持日常生活细节不变
- How're you getting on? - Just fine.
-参观得怎么样  -很好
Dick, can we borrow Mrs. Torrance for a few minutes?
迪克  能让托伦斯夫人跟我们来一下吗
We're on our way through to the basement.
我们正要去地下室
I promise we won't keep her very long.
我保证不会很久的
No problem, Mr. Ullman. I was just getting to the ice cream.
没问题  乌尔曼先生  我们正要去吃冰激凌
- You like ice cream, Doc? - Yeah.
-你喜欢冰激凌吧  博士  -喜欢
I thought you did.
我想也是
You folks don't mind
你们不介意
if I give Danny some ice cream while we waiting for you?
我带丹尼吃点冰激凌  边吃边等你们吧
- Not at all. - No, we don't mind.
-当然不  -不介意
- Good. - Sound good to you, Doc?
-好  -你觉得好不好  博士
- Yeah. - Okay, you behave yourself.
-好  -好  你要乖乖的哦
What kind of ice cream do you like, Doc?
你喜欢什么冰激凌  博士
Chocolate.
巧克力的
Chocolate it shall be. Come on, son.
那我们就吃巧克力口味的  来吧  孩子
It's amazing, how much activities going on today.
今天大家似乎都很忙乱啊
Yes. Well, the guests and some of the staff left yesterday,
是啊  昨天客人们还有一些员工离开了
but the last day's always hectic.
但停业前最后一天总是很忙乱
Everybody wants to be on their way as early as possible.
大家都想尽早上路离开
By 5 o'clock tonight, you'll never know anybody was ever here.
等到今晚5点  就像没人在这里存在过一样
- Just like a ghost ship, huh? - Yes.
-就像一艘幽灵船  -没错
Do you know how I knew your name was Doc?
你知道我是怎么知道你叫"博士"的吗
You know what I'm talking about, don't you?
你知道我在说什么  对吧
I can remember when I was a little boy,
我记得  我小时候
my grandmother and I could hold conversations
我奶奶和我全程不张嘴
entirely without ever opening our mouths.
就可以进行对话
She called it "Shining."
她称之为「闪灵」能力
And for a long time I thought
很久以来  我以为
it was just the two of us that had "the Shine" to us.
只有我们祖孙俩有这种能力
Just like you probably thought you was the only one.
就像你可能以为只有你一个人有一样
But there are other folks,
但其实还有别人
though mostly they don't know it, or don't believe it.
虽然他们自己不知道  或者不相信
How long have you been able to do it?
你从什么时候开始有这能力的
Why don't you want to talk about it?
你为什么不想说呢
I'm not supposed to.
我不应该说出来
Who says you ain't supposed to?
谁说你不应该说出来
Tony.
托尼
Who's Tony?
托尼是谁
Tony's the little boy that lives in my mouth.
托尼是住在我嘴里的小男孩
Is Tony the one that tells you things?
是托尼告诉你一些事的吗
Yes.
是的
How does he tell you things?
他是怎么告诉你那些事的
It's like I go to sleep, and he shows me things.
就好像我睡着以后  他给我看一些东西
But when I wake up, I can't remember everything.
但等我醒来  我什么都记不得了
Does your mom and dad know about Tony?
你爸妈知道托尼的存在吗
Yes.
知道
Do they know he tells you things?
他们知道他会告诉你一些事吗
Tony told me never to tell them.
托尼告诉我  千万别告诉他们
Has Tony ever told you anything about this place?
托尼跟你说过关于这里的一些事吗
About the Overlook Hotel?
关于眺望酒店
I don't know.
我不知道
Now think real hard, Doc.
好好想想  博士
Think.
想想
Maybe he showed me something.
也许他给我看过一点
Try to think of what it was.
努力想想是什么
Mr. Hallorann, are you scared of this place?
哈洛兰先生  你怕这里吗
No. Scared of nothing here.
不  我才不怕这里
It's just that...
只不过...
you know, some places are like people.
有些地方就跟人一样
Some shine and some don't.
有些有闪灵能力  有些没有
I guess you could say the Overlook Hotel
我觉得可以说眺望酒店
has something about it that's like shining.
就有类似于闪灵的能力
Is there something bad here?
这里有不好的东西吗
You know, Doc, when something happens...
其实  博士  当某件事发生之后
it can leave a trace of itself behind.
它会在身后留下踪迹
Say, like...
就比如说
if someone burns toast.
有人烤焦了吐司
Maybe things that happen leave other kind of traces behind.
也许某些事发生后会留下其他类型的踪迹
Not things that anyone can notice.
不是人人都能注意得到的踪迹
But things that people who shine can see.
只有拥有闪灵能力的人才能看到的踪迹
Just like they can see things that haven't happened yet...
就像他们能看见尚未发生的事情一样
sometimes they can see things that happened a long time ago.
有时他们也能看见很久以前发生的事
I think a lot of things happened right here
我觉得就这家酒店
in this particular hotel over the years.
多年来肯定发生过很多事
And not all of them was good.
并不全是好事
What about room 237?
237号房是怎么回事
Room 237?
237号房
You're scared of room 237, ain't you?
你害怕237号房  不是吗
No, I ain't.
不  我没有
Mr. Hallorann, what is in room 237?
哈洛兰先生  237号房里有什么
Nothing.
什么都没有
There ain't nothing in room 237.
237号房里什么都没有
But you ain't got no business going in there anyway.
但反正你也不需要进去做什么事
So stay out.
所以别进去
You understand? Stay out!
你明白吗  别进去
Good morning, hon.
早  亲爱的
Your breakfast is ready.
你的早餐好了
What time is it?
几点了
It's about 11:30.
大概11点半
Eleven-thirty, Jesus.
11点半  老天啊
I guess we've been staying up too late.
我们熬夜熬得太晚了
I know it.
我知道
I made them just the way you like them, sunny-side up.
我按你的喜好煎了蛋  只煎一面
Nice.
真棒
It's really pretty outside.
外面很漂亮
How about taking me for a walk after you finish your breakfast?
你吃完早餐之后  带我出去散散步怎么样
I suppose I ought to try to do some writing first.
我应该先试着写点东西
Any ideas yet?
有灵感了吗
Lots of ideas.
思如泉涌
No good ones.
可惜都算不上好
Well, something will come.
你会想到好点子的
It's just a matter of settling into the habit of writing every day.
关键是你得适应每天都写作的习惯
Yep. That's all it is.
是啊  那就是关键
It's really nice up here, isn't it?
这里真的很好  对吧
I love it.
我爱这里
I really do.
真的很爱
I've never been this happy or comfortable anywhere.
我从来没这么开心自在过
It's amazing how fast you get used to such a big place.
你这么快就适应了这大房子  真好
I tell you, when we first came up here,
我跟你说  我们刚来的时候
I thought it was kind of scary.
我还觉得这里有点吓人
I fell in love with it right away.
我立马就爱上了这里
When I came up here for my interview,
我过来面试的时候
it was as though I'd been here before.
就好像以前来过这里
I mean, we all have moments of déjà vu,
我们都有过似曾相识的感觉
but this was ridiculous.
但这也太离奇了
It was almost as though I knew
就好像我知道
what was going to be around every corner.
每个角落会有什么一样
The loser has to keep America clean. How's that?
输的人要打扫全美国  怎么样
- All right. - And you're going to lose.
-好啊  -你输定了
And I'm going to get you. You'd better run fast!
我要抓到你了  你最好跑快点
Look out!
小心
I'm coming in close. All right?
我要追上来了  知道吗
Loser has to keep America clean.
输的人要把美国打扫干净
- Oh, no! - Keep America clean.
眺望迷宫
Okay.
好吧
Danny, you win.
丹尼  你赢了
Let's take the rest of this walking.
剩下的路我们就走走吧
- Okay. - Whew.
-好  -真累
Give me your hand.
手给我
Isn't it beautiful?
很漂亮对吧
Yeah.
是啊
Dead end.
死路
Woo, we made it.
我们成功了
- Isn't it beautiful? - Yeah.
-很漂亮对吧  -是啊
It's so pretty.
真漂亮
Yeah.
是啊
I didn't think it was going to be this big. Did you?
我没想到会有这么大  你呢
Nope.
没想到
Rutherford was serving a life sentence...
卢瑟福德因为1968年的枪击案
for his conviction in the 1968 shooting.
被判处无期徒刑
And the search continues in the mountains near Uray today
警方仍在乌雷附近的山中
for that missing Aspen woman.
搜寻那位失踪的阿斯彭女子
Twenty-four-year-old Susan Robertson has been missing 10 days.
24岁的苏珊·罗伯森已失踪十天
She disappeared while on a hunting trip with her husband.
她在和丈夫外出打猎时失踪
They have good weather right now,
目前的天气很好
but they may have to call off the search...
但如果预计的暴风雪明日到达
if a predicted snowstorm moves in tomorrow.
他们可能不得不叫停搜索
But it's so beautiful in Denver today,
但是今天丹佛的天气这么好
it's hard to believe a snowstorm could be that close.
很难想象马上就会有暴风雪
I know. I want to go outside and lie in the sun.
我知道  我也想出去沐浴阳光
Yet to our north, to our west, it is snowing and cold.
但是我们的北面和西面都在下雪  很冷
And it's moving right here towards Colorado as we talk.
此刻  暴风雪正朝着科罗拉多州袭来
It's incredible.
真是难以置信
Hi, hon.
你好  亲爱的
How's it going?
怎么样了
Fine.
挺好的
Get a lot written today?
今天写了很多吗
Yes.
是的
Hey, the weather forecast said it's going to snow tonight.
话说  天气预报说今晚会下雪
What do you want me to do about it?
那你要我怎样
Come on, hon.
别这样  亲爱的
Don't be so grouchy.
别这么暴躁
I'm not...
我没有
being grouchy.
暴躁
I just want to finish my work.
我就是想完成作品
Okay. I understand.
好的  我明白
I'll come back later on with a couple of sandwiches for you and...
我一会儿再给你带几个三明治过来
maybe you'll let me read something then.
可能你就会让我看一点了
Wendy,
温蒂
let me explain something to you.
我跟你解释一下
Whenever you come in here and interrupt me,
只要你进来  打扰我
you're breaking my concentration.
你就让我没法集中注意力
You're distracting me,
你在让我分心
and it will then take me time to get back to where I was.
我要花很久才能回到之前的状态
Understand?
懂了吗
Yeah.
懂了
Fine.
很好
Now we're going to make a new rule.
我们要定一条新规矩
Whenever I'm in here
只要我在这里
and you hear me typing,
你听见我在打字
or whether you don't hear me typing,
或者你没听见我打字
or whatever the fuck you hear me doing in here,
或者不管你听见我在这里面做什么
when I'm in here, that means I am working,
只要我在这里  就意味着我在工作
that means don't come in.
也意味着不要进来
Now, do you think you can handle that?
这个你能做到吗
Yeah.
可以
Fine.
很好
Why don't you start right now and get the fuck out of here?
不如你就从现在开始  马上滚远点
Okay.
好吧
All right, you!
你够了
I know you've got more.
我知道你还有雪球
Missed!
没打中
Don't have!
没雪球了
No fair anymore.
不公平了
Oh, no.
别啊
I knew it.
我就知道
This is KDK 12 calling KDK 1.
KDK12号呼叫KDK1号
This is KDK 1. We're receiving you. Over.
我是KDK1号  我们听到了  完毕
Hi, this is Wendy Torrance at the Overlook Hotel.
你好  我是眺望酒店的温蒂·托伦斯
Hi, how are you folks getting on up there? Over.
你好  你们在山上如何  完毕
We're just fine.
我们挺好的
But our telephones don't seem to be doing too well.
但是我们的电话似乎坏了
Are the lines down, by any chance? Over.
有没有可能是电话线断了  完毕
Yes, quite a few of them are down due to the storm. Over.
没错  因为暴雪不少电话线都断了  完毕
Any chance of them being repaired soon? Over.
有可能尽快修好吗  完毕
Well, I wouldn't like to say.
我也不想这么说
Most winters they stay that way until spring. Over.
多数年份里  都要到春天才能修好  完毕
Boy, this storm is really something, isn't it? Over.
天啊  这暴风雪真的很强对吧  完毕
Yes. It's one of the worst we've had for years.
没错  这是近几年来最强的一次
Is there anything else we can do for you, Mrs. Torrance? Over.
有别的要帮忙的吗  托伦斯夫人  完毕
I suppose not. Over.
我觉得没了  完毕
If you folks have any problems up there, just give us a call.
如果你们在山上有麻烦  就跟我们联系
And, Mrs. Torrance?
另外  托伦斯夫人
I think it might be a good idea
我觉得你最好
if you leave your radio on all the time now. Over.
一直把无线电开着  完毕
Okay. We'll do that.
好的  那我们就开着
It was real nice talking to you.
跟你通话很愉快
Bye. Over and out.
再见  完毕  退出
Hello, Danny.
你好  丹尼
Come and play with us.
来和我们一起玩吧
Come and play with us, Danny.
来和我们一起玩吧  丹尼
For ever...
永远
Tony,
托尼
I'm scared.
我害怕
Remember what Mr. Hallorann said.
记住哈洛兰先生说的话
It's just like pictures in a book, Danny.
这就像书里的插画  丹尼
It isn't real.
这不是真的
Please let me give you some money.
我给你些钱吧
I wouldn't think of it.
我没想要钱
Well, how can I repay you?
那我该如何报答你
It's okay. Really.
没事的  真的
Well, I'm going to have some coffee.
我去煮一点咖啡
Would you like some?
你想喝吗
Sure.
好啊
Great. Sit down.
太好了  坐下
Ooh, these marvellous doughnuts. Help yourself.
好吃的甜甜圈  请自便
- Coffee will be ready in a few minutes. - Mom?
-咖啡过几分钟就好  -妈妈
Yeah?
怎么了
Can I go up to my room and get my fire-engine?
我可以去我的房间拿消防车吗
Not right now. Daddy's asleep.
现在不行  爸爸在睡觉
I won't make any noise.
我不会发出声音的
Come on, Doc.
别闹  博士
He only went to bed a few hours ago.
他几个小时之前才去睡觉
Can't you wait till later?
你不能等他起来再拿吗
I won't make a sound. I promise I'll tiptoe.
我不会发出声音的  我保证会踮着脚走
Well, all right.
那好吧
But really don't make a sound.
不过千万别发出声音
I won't, Mom.
我不会的  妈妈
Make sure you come right back,
你拿到了就马上回来
because I'm going to make lunch soon.
因为我很快要做午餐了
- Okay? - Okay, Mom.
-知道了吗  -知道了  妈妈
Can I go to my room and get my fire-engine?
我可以去我的房间拿消防车吗
Come here for a minute first.
先到这里来一下
How's it going, Doc?
你还好吗  博士
Okay.
挺好的
Having a good time?
玩得开心吗
Yes, Dad.
开心  爸爸
Good.
那就好
I want you to have a good time.
我希望你能开心
I am, Dad.
我很开心  爸爸
Dad?
爸爸
Yes?
怎么了
Do you feel bad?
你不舒服吗
No.
没有
I'm just a little bit tired.
我就是有点累
Then why don't you go to sleep?
那你为什么不睡觉
I can't.
我不能睡
I got too much to do.
我还有很多活要干
Dad?
爸爸
Yes?
怎么了
Do you like this hotel?
你喜欢这个酒店吗
Yes.
是啊
I do.
我喜欢
I love it.
我很爱它
Don't you?
你不喜欢吗
I guess so.
喜欢吧
Good.
那就好
I want you to like it here.
我希望你喜欢这里
I wish we could stay here forever...
我希望我们可以永远待在这里
and ever...
永远
Dad?
爸爸
What?
怎么了
You would never hurt Mommy or me, would you?
你永远不会伤害我和妈妈  对吧
What do you mean?
什么意思
Did your mother ever say that to you?
你妈妈跟你那么说过吗
That I would hurt you?
说我会伤害你们吗
No, Dad.
没有  爸爸
You sure?
你确定吗
Yes, Dad.
是的  爸爸
I love you, Danny.
我爱你  丹尼
I love you more than anything else in the whole world,
我爱你胜过全世界任何东西
and I would never do anything to hurt you,
我绝不会伤害你
never.
绝对不会
You know that, don't you?
你知道的  对吧
Yes, Dad.
是的  爸爸
Good.
很好
Mom?
妈妈
Mom, are you in there?
妈妈  你在里面吗
Jack!
杰克
Jack? Jack!
杰克  杰克
What happened?
出什么事了
Honey...
亲爱的
Jack?
杰克
I had the most terrible nightmare I ever had.
我做了一个这辈子最可怕的噩梦
- It was the most horrible dream. - It's okay, it's okay now.
-最可怕的噩梦  -没事了  已经没事了
Really.
真的
I dreamed that I...
我梦到我...
that I killed you and Danny.
杀了你和丹尼
But I didn't just kill you.
但我不只是杀死了你们
I cut you up into little pieces.
我还将你们剁成碎块
My God.
我的天
I must be losing my mind.
我肯定是疯了
Everything's going to be all right.
一切都会好起来的
Come on. Let's get up off the floor.
来  先起来
It's okay. There. Now sit up.
没事了  来  坐好
It's okay.
没事了
Danny!
丹尼
Everything's okay!
这里没事
Just go play in your room for a while.
你先回自己房间玩一会儿
Your dad's just got a headache.
你爸爸只是有点头疼
Danny, mind what I say. Go play in your room.
丹尼  听我的话  回自己房间玩去
Honey, let me just go get him out of here.
亲爱的  我先把他带走
I'll be right back.
我马上就回来
Danny.
丹尼
Why don't you mind me?
你为什么不听我的话
Oh, my God.
我的天
Danny, what happened to your neck?
丹尼  你的脖子怎么了
You did this to him...
是你弄伤了他
didn't you?!
是不是
You son of a bitch!
你这个混蛋
You did this to him!
是你弄伤了他
Didn't you?!
是不是
How could you?!
你怎么能这样
God! I'd give anything for a drink.
老天  要能喝杯酒我愿意付出一切
I'd give my goddamn soul...
我愿意出卖灵魂
for just a glass of beer.
换一杯啤酒
Hi, Lloyd.
嗨  劳埃德
A little slow tonight, isn't it?
今晚有些无聊  不是吗
Yes, it is, Mr. Torrance.
是的  托伦斯先生
What will it be?
您要喝什么
I'm awfully glad you asked me that, Lloyd...
我很高兴你问出了这句话  劳埃德
because I just happen to have two twenties
因为我钱包里刚好有两张二十美元
and two tens right here in my wallet.
和两张十美元的钞票
I was afraid they were going to be there until next April.
我本来还担心明年四月前都花不出去了
So here's what:
你听好
You slip me a bottle of bourbon...
给我一瓶波旁酒
A little glass and some ice.
一个玻璃杯和一些冰
You can do that, can't you, Lloyd?
你能做到的  对吗  劳埃德
You're not too busy, are you?
你不会忙不过来的  对吗
No, sir. I'm not busy at all.
不会  先生  我一点也不忙
Good man.
好样的
You set them up and I'll knock them back, Lloyd,
你给我倒一杯  我就喝光一杯  劳埃德
one by one.
一杯接一杯
White man's burden, Lloyd, my man.
白人的负担  劳埃德  伙计
White man's burden.
白人的负担
Say, Lloyd...
劳埃德
it seems I'm temporarily light.
我暂时囊中羞涩
How's my credit in this joint, anyway?
我在这里的信用怎么样
Your credit's fine, Mr. Torrance.
您的信用没问题  托伦斯先生
That's swell.
那太好了
I like you, Lloyd.
我喜欢你  劳埃德
I always liked you.
我一直很喜欢你
You were always the best of them.
你一直是最优秀的
Best goddamned bartender from Timbuktu to Portland, Maine.
从廷巴克图到缅因州的波特兰  最优秀的酒保
Or Portland, Oregon, for that matter.
或者是俄勒冈州的波特兰
Thank you for saying so.
谢谢您这么说
Here's to five miserable months on the wagon
敬我戒酒的这悲惨的五个月
and all the irreparable harm that it's caused me.
以及它给我造成的无法弥补的伤害
How are things going, Mr. Torrance?
您过得还好吗  托伦斯先生
Things could be better, Lloyd.
不是很好  劳埃德
Things could be a whole lot better.
非常不好
I hope it's nothing serious.
我希望不是什么大事
No.
不
Nothing serious.
不是大事
Just a little problem with the old sperm bank upstairs.
不过是跟楼上那个"精子银行"发生了点口角
Nothing I can't handle, though, Lloyd.
不过我都能应付  劳埃德
Thanks.
谢了
Women.
女人啊
Can't live with them
受不了她们
can't live without them.
却又少不了她们
Words of wisdom, Lloyd.
至理名言  劳埃德
Words of wisdom.
至理名言
I never laid a hand on him, goddamn it.
我根本没打过他  该死的
I didn't.
我没有
I wouldn't touch one hair on his goddamn little head.
我都舍不得碰他那小脑袋上的一根头发
I love the little son of a bitch.
我爱那个小混蛋
I'd do anything for him.
我愿意为他做任何事
Any fucking thing for him.
真他妈是任何事
But that bitch!
但那个贱人
As long as I live...
只要我还活着
she'll never let me forget what happened.
她就不会让我忘记以前的事
I did hurt him once, okay?
我确实伤过他一次  行了吧
It was an accident.
那是个意外
Completely unintentional.
我完全是无意的
It could have happened to anybody.
那可能发生在任何人身上
And it was three goddamn years ago!
那已经是他妈三年前的事了
The little fucker had thrown all my papers all over the floor.
那个小鬼把我的稿子丢得满地都是
All I tried to do was pull him up.
我只是想把他拉起来
A momentary loss of muscular coordination.
稍微丧失了一下肌肉协调能力
I mean...
我是指...
A few extra foot-pounds of energy...
多用了那么一点点力气
per second, per second.
就那一秒  那一秒
Jack!
杰克
Thank God you're here.
谢天谢地你在这
There's someone else in the hotel with us.
酒店里除了我们还有其他人
There's a crazy woman in one of the rooms.
某间房里有个疯女人
She tried to strangle Danny.
她想勒死丹尼
Are you out of your fucking mind?
你他妈疯了吗
No.
不是
It's the truth! Really.
是真的  真的
I swear it. Danny told me.
我发誓  是丹尼告诉我的
He went up into one of the bedrooms.
他跑到某间卧室里
The door was open, and he saw this crazy woman in the bathtub.
房门开着  他看到浴缸里有个疯女人
She tried to strangle him!
她想勒死他
Which room was it?
是哪间房
From Channel 10 in Miami...
迈阿密十频道
this is Newswatch
欢迎收看《新闻观察》
with Glenn Rinker, Ann Bishop,
由格伦·林克  安·毕肖普
and the award-winning Newswatch team.
及《新闻观察》获奖制作团队为您呈现
Good evening. I'm Glenn Rinker, Newswatch Ten.
晚上好  我是十频道《新闻观察》的格伦·林克
While Miami continues to swelter in a record winter heatwave
迈阿密冬季热浪刷新纪录  持续闷热难耐
bringing temperatures to the mid and upper nineties,
气温上升到90多华氏度左右
the Central and Rocky Mountain States are buried in snow.
而中部和落基山脉覆盖的各州则被大雪覆盖
In Colorado,
在科罗拉多州
10 inches of snow has fallen in just a few hours tonight.
今晚不过短短数小时  降雪量就达10英寸
Travel in the Rockies is almost impossible.
在落基山脉通行变成几乎不可能的事了
Airports are shut down, stranding thousands of passengers.
机场关闭  成千上万名旅客滞留
Highways are blocked by snowdrifts.
高速公路被积雪堵住
Railroad tracks are frozen.
铁轨冻结
Officials in Colorado tell Newswatch...
科罗拉多州官方告知《新闻观察》
at least three have been killed by exposure to freezing winds.
至少已有三人因暴露在寒风中死亡
The governor of Colorado is expected tomorrow
科罗拉多州州长预计将在明天
to declare a weather emergency.
宣布天气紧急状况
The National Guard might be called out...
国民警卫队可能会被派遣
to clear streets and roads.
去清空街道和道路
Weather forecasters predict more snow...
天气预报员预测今夜至明天
and heavy winds tonight and tomorrow...
会有更多降雪及强风
with temperatures dropping well below zero.
气温将会降到零华氏度以下
Back here in south Florida, we've got the opposite problem.
佛罗里达南部这里  我们的问题正相反
The heat and humidity are supposed to climb.
温度和湿度预计会上升
Local beaches should be jammed.
本地海滩将人满为患
Our weather expert, Walter Cronice...
我们的天气专家沃特·克罗莱斯
will have the local forecast later on Newswatch.
稍后将在《新闻观察》中带来本地天气预报
We're sorry. Your call cannot be completed as dialed.
很抱歉  您拨打的电话无法接通
If you need assistance, please call the operator.
如需要协助  请打给接线员
Jack?
杰克
Yes, it's me.
没错  是我
Thank God.
谢天谢地
Did you find anything?
你找到什么了吗
No. Nothing at all.
没有  什么都没有
I didn't see one goddamn thing.
我什么都没看到
You went into the room Danny said? To 237?
你去的是丹尼说的房间吗  237号房
Yes, I did.
是的  我去了
And you didn't see anything at all?
你什么都没看到吗
Absolutely nothing.
什么都没有
How is he?
他怎么样了
He's still asleep.
他还在睡
Good.
那就好
I'm sure he'll be himself again in the morning.
他肯定明天早上就会恢复正常了
Are you sure it was the right room?
你确定你没找错房间吗
I mean, maybe Danny made a mistake.
我是说  或许是丹尼记错了
He must have gone in that room.
他去的肯定是那间房
The door was open, the lights were on.
房门开着  灯也开着
I just don't understand it.
我只是不明白
What about those bruises on his neck?
他脖子上的淤伤是怎么回事
Somebody did that to him.
肯定是有人掐的
I think...
我想...
he did it to himself.
是他自己掐的
No.
不
That's not possible.
那不可能
Wendy...
温蒂
once you rule out his version of what happened...
一旦我们排除他的说法
there is no other explanation.
事情就没有其他解释了
Is there?
不是吗
It wouldn't be that different from the episode...
这和我们到这里来之前
that he had before we came up here.
他的那次发作差不多
Would it?
不是吗
Oh, Jack.
杰克
Whatever the explanation is...
无论解释是什么
I think we...
我觉得我们...
have to get Danny out of here.
得带丹尼离开这里
Get him out of here?
带他离开这里
Yes.
是的
You mean just leave the hotel?
你是说直接离开这家酒店
It is so fucking typical of you to create a problem like this
你他妈就会没事找事
when I finally have a chance to accomplish something!
我好不容易有机会能做出点成果
When I'm really into my work!
我好不容易一心扑在写作上
I could really write my own ticket
如果我现在回博尔德
if I went back to Boulder now, couldn't I?
就可以随心所欲了  是吗
Shoveling out driveways, work in a car wash.
给车道铲雪  在洗车场打工
- Any of that appeal to you? - Jack...
-你觉得这些工作很好是吗  -杰克
Wendy, I have let you fuck up my life so far,
温蒂  我一直都在纵容你搞砸我的人生
but I am not going to let you fuck this up.
但我绝不允许你搞砸我这次的机会
Good evening. Forest Service.
晚上好  这里是林业局
Hello, my name is Dick Hallorann.
你好  我叫迪克·哈洛兰
I'm the head chef up at the Overlook Hotel.
我是眺望酒店的厨师长
Good evening, Mr. Hallorann. What can I do for you?
晚上好  哈洛兰先生  请问有什么事吗
Sir, I've been trying to make an urgent phone call up there,
先生  我一直想打个紧急电话去酒店
but the operator said that the phone lines are down.
但接线员说电话线路都瘫痪了
Yeah, I'm afraid a lot of lines around here are down
是啊  恐怕这附近的许多电话线路
due to the storm.
都因为暴风雪断掉了
Well, look sir, I hate to put you through any trouble,
是这样的  先生  我也不想麻烦你
but there's a family up there all by themselves with a young kid,
但酒店里住着一家人  带着个小孩
and with this storm and everything...
现在又来了这么大的暴风雪
I'd sure appreciate it if you'd give them a call on your radio
能不能拜托你用无线电联系一下他们
just to see if everything's okay.
确保没出什么事
I'll be glad to do that, sir.
我很乐意帮这个忙  先生
Why don't you call me back in about 20 minutes?
你等20分钟后再打过来吧
Thank you very much. I'll do that.
非常感谢你  我会的
All right, sir.
那先这样  先生
Good evening, Mr. Torrance.
晚上好  托伦斯先生
Good evening.
晚上好
Hi, Lloyd.
嗨  劳埃德
I've been away, but now I'm back.
我离开了一阵  不过现在回来了
Good evening, Mr. Torrance.
晚上好  托伦斯先生
It's good to see you.
很高兴见到你
It's good to be back, Lloyd.
回来的感觉真好  劳埃德
What'll it be, sir?
您想喝点什么  先生
Hair of the dog that bit me.
解醉酒
Bourbon on the rocks.
波旁威士忌加冰块
That'll do her.
就它了
No charge to you, Mr. Torrance.
不用给钱  托伦斯先生
No charge?
不要钱
Your money's no good here.
你的钱在这里用不上
Orders from the house.
免费赠送
Drink up, Mr. Torrance.
喝吧  托伦斯先生
I'm the kind of man likes to know who's buying their drinks, Lloyd.
我这人喜欢搞清楚是谁在请客  劳埃德
It's not a matter that concerns you, Mr. Torrance.
您不用操心这事  托伦斯先生
At least, not at this point.
至少现在不用
Anything you say, Lloyd.
那就听你的  劳埃德
Anything you say.
就听你的
Oh, dear! Oh, dear! I'm so sorry, sir.
天呐  天呐  非常抱歉  先生
Oh, dear. Oh, dear.
我的天呐
I've made an awful mess of your jacket, sir.
我把您的夹克衫弄脏了  先生
Oh, that's all right. I've got plenty of jackets.
没关系  我有很多件夹克衫
I'm afraid it's advocaat, sir. It tends to stain.
因为这是蛋黄酒  先生  所以会留下污渍
Advocaat, is it?
蛋黄酒吗
Yes, sir. Look, I think the best thing
是的  先生  我觉得最好的办法
is to come along to the gentlemen's room, sir,
就是您跟我一起去卫生间清理  先生
and we'll get some water to it, sir.
我们可以用水擦掉  先生
Looks as though you might have got a spot of it on yourself there,
看样子你的衣服上也被溅到了
Jeevesy old boy.
侍者先生
That doesn't matter, sir. You...
不要紧的  先生  您..
You're the important one.
您才是贵客
Awfully nice of you to say.
你这么说真是太贴心了
Of course, I intended to change my jacket this evening
当然了  我还是打算先换掉夹克衫
before the fish and goose soiree.
再去参加今晚的高级晚会
Very wise, sir. Very wise.
太明智了  先生
Here. I'll just hold this for you there, Jeevesy.
来  我帮你开着门  侍者先生
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
谢谢您  先生  谢谢
Now let's see if we can improve this with a little water, sir.
来看看能不能用水擦干净  先生
All right. I'll just...
好的  那我就...
set my bourbon and advocaat down right there.
把我的波旁威士忌和蛋黄酒放这里
Won't keep you a moment, sir.
不会耽误您太多时间  先生
Fine.
好的
What do they call you around here, Jeevesy?
这里的人都是怎么称呼你的  侍者先生
Grady, sir. Delbert Grady.
格拉迪  先生  德尔波特·格拉迪
Grady?
格拉迪
Yes, sir.
是的  先生
Delbert Grady.
德尔波特·格拉迪
That's right, sir.
没错  先生
Mr. Grady...
格拉迪先生
Haven't I seen you somewhere before?
我们之前是不是在哪里见过
Why, no, sir. I don't believe so.
怎么会  先生  我想应该没有
It's coming off now, sir.
都擦掉了  先生
Mr. Grady,
格拉迪先生
weren't you once the caretaker here?
你以前在这里当过管理员吧
Why, no, sir. I don't believe so.
怎么会  先生  恐怕不是
You a married man, are you, Mr. Grady?
你结婚了  对吧  格拉迪先生
Yes, sir.
是的  先生
I have a wife and two daughters, sir.
我有个老婆和两个女儿  先生
And...
那么...
where are they now?
她们现在在哪里
They're somewhere around.
就在这附近吧
I'm not quite sure at the moment, sir.
此刻我也不太清楚  先生
Mr. Grady,
格拉迪先生
you were the caretaker here.
你曾经就是这里的管理员
I recognize you.
我认得你
I saw your picture in the newspapers.
我在报纸上看过你的照片
You...
你...
chopped your wife and daughters up into little bits.
把你的妻子女儿大卸八块
And...
然后
and you blew your brains out.
一枪爆头自杀了
That's strange, sir.
这就奇怪了  先生
I don't have any recollection of that at all.
我一点印象都没有
Mr. Grady,
格拉迪先生
you were the caretaker here.
你曾经就是这里的管理员
I'm sorry to differ with you, sir.
抱歉我不敢苟同  先生
But you
但你...
are the caretaker.
才是这里现在的管理员
You've always been the caretaker.
你一直都是这里的管理员
I should know, sir.
我很清楚  先生
I've always been here.
因为我一直都在这里
Did you know, Mr. Torrance,
你知道吗  托伦斯先生
that your son...
你儿子...
is attempting to bring an outside party into this situation?
正打算带外人进来搅局
Did you know that?
你知道吗
No.
不知道
He is, Mr. Torrance.
是真的  托伦斯先生
Who?
谁
A nigger.
一个黑人
A nigger?
黑人
A nigger cook.
一个黑人厨师
How?
怎么做到
Your son has a very great talent.
你儿子拥有一种超凡的才能
I don't think you are aware how great it is,
我觉得你还不清楚那究竟有多超凡
but he is attempting to use that very talent
但他正打算使用这一才能
against your will.
违背你的意愿
He is a very willful boy.
他的确是个任性的孩子
Indeed he is, Mr. Torrance.
没错  托伦斯先生
A very willful boy.
一个非常任性的孩子
A rather naughty boy,
一个非常调皮的孩子
if I may be so bold, sir.
请恕我大胆直言  先生
It's his mother.
是因为他的母亲
She interferes.
她喜欢胡乱干预
Perhaps they need a good talking-to.
或许该好好跟他们谈谈了
If you don't mind my saying so.
希望你别介意我这么说
Perhaps a bit more.
或许要采取更严厉的手段
My girls, sir,
我的两个女儿  先生
they didn't care for the Overlook at first.
她们一开始毫不关心眺望酒店
One of them actually stole a pack of matches
其中一个还偷了一盒火柴
and tried to burn it down.
想要放火烧了这里
But I corrected them, sir.
但我纠正了她们  先生
And when my wife tried to prevent me from doing my duty,
当我妻子试图阻止我履行职责时
I corrected her.
我也纠正了她
We have the Snowcat.
我们有雪地车
If the weather breaks,
如果天气放晴
we might just be able to get down the mountain in that.
我们也许能开雪地车下山
I could call the forest rangers first
我可以先跟护林员打个电话
and then tell them that we're coming
告诉他们我们要来了
so that they could start searching for us, in case we didn't make it.
如果我们遇到了麻烦  他们还能来找我们
And if Jack won't come with us,
如果杰克不肯跟我们走
we'll just have to tell him that we're going by ourselves.
直接告诉他我们自己走就行了
That's all there is to it.
只能这样了
Redrum.
红朗姆
Redrum. Redrum.
红朗姆  红朗姆
- Danny? - Redrum.
-丹尼  -红朗姆
- Redrum. - Danny, what's the matter, hon?
-红朗姆  -丹尼  怎么了  宝贝
Redrum!
红朗姆
Are you having a bad dream?
你是做噩梦了吗
Danny?
丹尼
Hon?
宝贝
Danny's not here, Mrs. Torrance.
丹尼不在这里  托伦斯夫人
Come on, hon.
好了  宝贝
Wake up.
快醒过来
You just had a bad dream.
你只是做了个噩梦
Everything's okay.
一切都没事
Danny can't wake up, Mrs. Torrance.
丹尼醒不过来  托伦斯夫人
Danny.
丹尼
Wake up!
醒醒
Come on.
快啊
Right now.
快醒醒
Wake up!
醒醒啊
Danny's gone away, Mrs. Torrance.
丹尼已经走了  托伦斯夫人
Danny.
丹尼
This is KDK 1 calling KDK 12.
KDK1号呼叫KDK12号
Are you receiving me?
能收到吗
Do you read me?
能听到吗
This is KDK 1 calling KDK 12.
KDK1号呼叫KDK12号
Are you receiving me?
能收到吗
Do you read me?
能听到吗
This is KDK 1 calling KDK 12.
KDK1号呼叫KDK12号
KDK 1 calling KDK 12. Are you receiv-
KDK1号呼叫KDK12号  能收到...
Good evening. Forest service.
晚上好  这里是林业局
Hello. This is Dick Hallorann again.
你好  又是我  迪克·哈洛兰
I called a while ago about the folks at the Overlook Hotel.
我之前打过电话  询问眺望酒店的人是否平安
Oh, yeah.
对  没错
We tried to contact them several times by radio
我们尝试用无线电联系他们好几次
but they didn't answer.
但他们没回复
Maybe they got their radio turned off
也许他们把无线电关了
or they are in a place where they can't hear it.
或是他们恰好在一个听不到呼叫的地方
If you'd like, I'd be glad to try again later on.
如果你希望  我很乐意待会儿再试试
That's very nice of you.
你真的很好心
I'll call you back later.
我晚点再打给你
Bye.
再见
Pardon me, miss. What time will we get to Denver?
请问一下  女士  我们几点能到丹佛
We're due to arrive at 8:20, sir.
预计8点20到达  先生
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
Can I speak to Larry?
我想找莱瑞
Speaking.
我就是
Hi, Larry. This is Dick. Dick Hallorann.
你好  莱瑞  我是迪克  迪克·哈洛兰
Dick! How you doing?
迪克  你还好吗
How's the weather down there?
你那里天气如何
I'm not in Florida, Larry.
我不在佛罗里达  莱瑞
I'm calling from Stapleton Airport.
我现在在斯台普顿机场给你打电话
What the hell are you doing down there?
你跑到那里干什么
I just got in from Miami. I got to get to the Overlook today.
我刚从迈阿密飞来  今天得赶去眺望酒店
What's the weather like there?
那边的天气怎么样
The snowplows are keeping things moving in town...
城里一直用扫雪机清除路面上的雪
but the mountain roads are blocked.
但山路全被雪封住了
Then I'm going to need a Snowcat to get up there.
那我得开雪地车才能上山了
Can you fix me up with one?
你能帮我找一辆吗
What's the big deal about getting there today...
有什么要紧事  你非得今天上山
especially in this kind of weather?
尤其天气还这么糟
Larry, just between you and me,
莱瑞  私下里跟你说
we got a very serious problem with the people
看守酒店的那家人
who are taking care of the place.
有重大问题
They turned out to be completely unreliable assholes.
没想到他们是完全靠不住的混蛋
Ullman phoned me last night.
乌尔曼昨晚打给我
And I'm supposed to go up there
叫我上山去酒店一趟
and find out if they have to be replaced.
看看是否需要换掉他们
How long will it take you to get up here?
你过来这里要花多长时间
About five hours.
大约五小时
I'm going to rent a car here at the airport.
我会在机场这里租一辆车
Okay, Dick, I'll take care of it.
好  迪克  我会帮你准备好的
Thanks a lot, Larry. I really appreciate that.
太谢谢你了  莱瑞  感激不尽
That's all right. Drive carefully.
不客气  小心驾驶
Well, good morning to you,
各位早上好
You're with Hal and Charlie on Radio 63, KHOW, Denver.
欢迎收听丹佛KHOW63台  我们是哈尔和查理
And Charlie, we have what you call your bad day out there.
查理  今天天气真的糟透了
What you call your heavy snow,
现在天降大雪
snowing hard throughout the Denver metro area.
整个丹佛地区都在下大雪
Many mountain passes...
很多山路...
Wolf Creek and Red Mountain passes are already closed...
狼溪和红山山路都已封闭
and the chain law is in effect right now at the Eisenhower Tunnel.
艾森豪威尔隧道也已封闭
I guess as we've just heard from the news forecast,
据新闻部门刚刚的消息
only a few flights are landing at Stapleton Airport.
只有寥寥几个航班在斯台普顿机场降落
and, with these early storms like this,
暴风雪这么早就开始侵袭
I guess the entire airport will probably be closed within the hour.
我估计一小时内整个机场都会关闭
Yeah, they're just not prepared.
没错  他们没有做好应对准备
The storm will continue through the day
暴风雪会持续一整天
and the National Weather Service
国家气象局
has declared a stockman's and traveler's advisory
已向市区外围所有地区的
for all areas outlying the Denver metro region.
畜牧业者和旅客发布警报
Get the cows in the barn.
把牛都赶进棚里
There you go.  Many businesses...
没错  很多商业...
Hon?
宝贝
Listen to me for a minute, will you?
你先听我说  好吗
I'm just going to go and talk to Daddy for a few minutes...
我要去找爸爸谈一下
and I'll be right back.
我很快就回来
I want you to just stay here...
我要你乖乖待在这里
and watch your cartoons, okay?
看卡通片  好吗
Okay, hon?
好吗  宝贝
Yes, Mrs. Torrance.
好的  托伦斯夫人
All right.
好了
I'll- I'll be back in just about five minutes.
我大概五分钟后就回来
I'm going to lock the door behind me.
我会把门锁上
Jack?
杰克
How do you like it?
你觉得怎么样
Jack.
杰克
What are you doing down here?
你下来这里做什么
I just...
我只是...
wanted...
想...
to talk to you.
跟你谈谈
Okay.
好啊
Let's talk.
来谈吧
What do you want to talk about?
你想谈什么
I...
我...
I can't really remember.
我不记得了
You can't remember.
你不记得了
No... I can't.
是啊  我不记得了
Maybe it was about Danny?
也许是跟丹尼有关
Maybe it was about him.
也许跟他有关
I think we should discuss Danny.
我觉得我们应该商量下丹尼的事
I think...
我觉得...
we should discuss what should be done with him.
我们该商量下该如何处置他
What should be done with him?
该如何处置他呢
I don't know.
我不知道
I don't think that's true.
我认为这不是真话
I think you have some very definite ideas...
我认为你已经有明确的想法
about what should be done with Danny.
该如何处置丹尼
And I'd like to know what they are.
我想知道你的想法
Well, I...
我...
I think maybe he should be taken to a doctor.
我觉得或许该带他去看医生
You think "maybe" he should be taken to a doctor?
你觉得"或许"该带他去看医生
Yes.
是的
When do you think "maybe" he should be taken to a doctor?
你觉得"或许"该何时带他去看医生呢
As soon as possible?
尽快
"As soon as possible?"
"尽快"
Jack.
杰克
Please.
求求你
You believe his health might be at stake.
你认为他的健康可能出现问题了
Yes.
是的
And you are concerned about him.
你很担心他
And are you concerned about me?
那你担心我吗
Of course I am.
我当然担心你了
Of course you are!
你当然担心我了
Have you ever thought about my responsibilities?
你有没有考虑过我的责任
Oh, Jack, what are you talking about?
杰克  你在说什么
Have you ever had a single moment's
你有没有那么一刻
thought about my responsibilities?
考虑过我的责任
Have you ever thought for a single solitary moment
你有没有那么一瞬间
about my responsibilities to my employers?!
考虑过我对我雇主的责任
Has it ever occurred to you
你有没有想过
that I have agreed to look after the hotel until May 1st?
我答应了照看这家酒店直到5月1号
Does it matter to you at all
难道你丝毫不在意
that the owners have placed their complete confidence and trust in me
酒店老板们对我的信心和信任吗
and that I have signed a letter of agreement.
我还签了一份协议书
A contract
一份合同
in which I've accepted that responsibility?
代表我接受了这份责任
Do you have the slightest idea
你到底知不知道
what a moral and ethical principal is? Do you?!
什么是做人的道德准则  你知道吗
Has it ever occurred to you what would happen to my future
你有没有想过  如果我未能履行自己的职责
if I fail to live up to my responsibilities?
那会对我的未来造成什么影响
Has it ever occurred to you? Has it?!
你到底有没有想过  有没有
Stay away from me!
离我远点
Why?
为什么
I just want to go back to my room.
我只想回我的房间
I'm very confused.
我很混乱
And I just need a chance to think things over.
我需要个机会好好想清楚
You've had your whole fucking life to think things over!
你已经有一辈子的时间可以好好想清楚
What good's a few minutes more going to do you now?
现在再多想区区几分钟又有什么用
Stay away from me!
离我远点
Please!
求你了
Don't hurt me.
别伤害我
I'm not going to hurt you.
我不会伤害你的
Stay away from me!
离我远点
- Wendy. - Stay away!
-温蒂  -走开
Darling.
亲爱的
Light of my life.
我的生命之光
I'm not going to hurt you.
我是不会伤害你的
You didn't let me finish my sentence.
你没让我说完
I said, "I'm not going to hurt you. "
我说  "我不会伤害你的"
I'm just going to bash your brains in.
我只会把你的脑袋砸烂
I'm going to bash them right the fuck in.
我会把你打得脑浆四溅
Stay away from me!
别过来
Don't hurt me!
别伤害我
I'm not going to hurt you.
我不会伤害你的
Stay away from me!
离我远点
Stay away!
别过来
Please!
求你了
Stop swinging the bat.
别再挥球棒了
Stay away from me.
离我远点
Put that bat down, Wendy.
把球棒放下  温蒂
Stop it!
停下
Wendy.
温蒂
Give me the bat.
把球棒给我
Please!
求你了
- Stay away! - Give me the bat.
-离我远点  -把球棒给我
Stop it!
停下
- Give me the bat. - Jack.
-把球棒给我  -杰克
- Stay away from me. - Stop swinging the bat.
-离我远点  -别挥球棒了
Please stop!
停下吧
Give me the bat.
把球棒给我
- Stay away from me. - Wendy.
-离我远点  -温蒂
- Stop it! - Give me the bat.
-停下  -把球棒给我
- Stay away! - Give me the bat.
-离我远点  -把球棒给我
Goddamn-!
该死的
What are you doing?
你在做什么
Wait a minute.
等等
Open the door!
把门打开
Goddamn it!
该死的
Let me out of here! Open the goddamn door!
放我出去  把该死的门打开
Wendy, listen.
温蒂  听着
Let me out and I'll forget the whole goddamn thing.
放我出去  整件事我就不追究了
It'll be just like nothing ever happened.
就像从没发生过一样
Wendy. Baby.
温蒂  宝贝
I think you hurt my head real bad.
我觉得你把我的头伤得很重
I'm dizzy.
我头晕
I need a doctor.
我需要看医生
Honey.
亲爱的
Don't leave me in here.
别把我丢在这
I'm going to go now.
我要走了
I'm going to try to ...
我打算拼尽全力...
get Danny down the Sidewinder...
带丹尼回萨德温德镇
in the Snowcat today.
坐雪地车走
I'll bring back a doctor.
我会带个医生回来
Wendy.
温蒂
I'm going to go now.
我要走了
Yes?
怎么了
You've got a big surprise coming to you.
有个巨大的惊喜在等着你
You're not going anywhere.
你休想去任何地方
Go check out the Snowcat and the radio,
去检查下雪地车和无线电
and you'll see what I mean.
你就会明白我的意思了
Go check it out.
去看看吧
Wendy?
温蒂
It's Grady, Mr. Torrance.
我是格拉迪  托伦斯先生
Delbert Grady.
德尔波特·格拉迪
Grady?
格拉迪
Grady, uh...
格拉迪  那个...
Hello, Grady.
你好  格拉迪
Mr. Torrance...
托伦斯先生
I see you can hardly have taken care of the...
看来你没能完成...
business we discussed.
我们讨论过的事宜
No need to rub it in, Mr. Grady.
没必要跑来奚落我  格拉迪先生
I'll deal with that situation as soon as I get out of here.
我一出去  就会处理好这个麻烦
Will you indeed, Mr. Torrance?
是吗  托伦斯先生
I wonder.
我不是很信
I have my doubts.
我表示怀疑
I, and others, have come to believe...
我和其他人已经开始认定
that your heart is not in this.
你的心思不在这上面
That you haven't the belly for it.
你没有足够的胆识来干这事
Just give me one more chance to prove it, Mr. Grady.
再给我一次机会证明自己  格拉迪先生
That's all I ask.
我就这一个请求
Your wife appears to be stronger than we imagined, Mr. Torrance.
你妻子似乎比我们预想的要强大  托伦斯先生
Somewhat more...
更加...
resourceful.
有智谋
She seems to have got the better of you.
她似乎占了上风
For the moment, Mr. Grady.
暂时的而已  格拉迪先生
Only for the moment.
暂时的而已
I fear you will have to deal with this matter...
恐怕你必须解决这个问题
in the harshest possible way, Mr. Torrance.
以最残酷的方式  托伦斯先生
I fear...
恐怕...
that is the only thing to do.
只能这样了
There's nothing I look forward to with greater pleasure, Mr. Grady.
我非常乐意这么做  格拉迪先生
You give your word on that, do you, Mr. Torrance?
你保证吗  托伦斯先生
I give you my word.
我保证
Redrum.
红朗姆
- Redrum. - Danny, stop it!
-红朗姆  -丹尼  停下
- Redrum. - Danny!
-红朗姆  -丹尼
Redrum.
红朗姆
Wendy?
温蒂
I'm home.
我回家了
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
出来  出来  不管你在哪里
Danny.
丹尼
I can't get out.
我出不来
Run!
快跑
Run and hide!
快去躲起来
Quick!
快点
Little pigs, little pigs, let me come in.
小猪小猪  放我进去
Not by the hair on your chinny-chin-chin?
痴心妄想  灰狼滚开
Then I'll huff...
我就吹啊
and I'll blow your house in!
把你的房子吹个底朝天
No!
不要
Jack.
杰克
Please!
求你了
Don't!
别这样
Stop it!
停下
Here's Johnny!
约翰尼来啦
Hello?
有人吗
Anybody here?
有人在吗
Danny?
丹尼
Danny-boy!
小丹尼
I'm coming!
我来了
I'm coming, Dan!
我来了  丹
Danny.
丹尼
Great party, isn't it?
派对很棒吧
I'm coming!!
我来了
You can't get away!
你跑不掉的
I'm right behind you!
我就在你后面
Danny.
丹尼
- Danny! - Mommy!
-丹尼  -妈妈
- Danny, come here! - Mommy!
-丹尼  过来  -妈妈
Danny.
丹尼
Mommy.
妈妈
Where...?
你们在哪...